Srivatsan Thumati Balaji

Full Stack Developer

srivatsantb@gmail.com

+917845774670

kryptocodes.github.io

Profile

I am a young and driven Full Stack Developer with more than two years of experience, DevOps and system administration experience alongside. I have successfully deployed and maintained multiple web apps with large userbases as well as contributed to open source projects and continue to do so.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript (TypeScript), Python, C, Bash

Frameworks: Gatsby, Next, Express, React Native, Django

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis

Tools & Technologies: Git, Babel, Jenkins, Figma

DevOps: AWS, Docker, SSH, Ngnix

Operating Systems: Linux, Windows

Experience

React Developer Saram Products

October 2020 - Present

Designed UI Logic and data structure, Created a fully functional React SPA with Node JS (GraphQL and PostgreSQL). Worked on Severless (Firebase) and SaaS CRM. UI/UX overhaul and performance enhancement resulting in by 70% load time improvement.

Lead Web Developer and Co Founder FOSS CLUB

September 2018 - Present

Built and maintained internal websites using React. Extended internal front-end component library in React with Styled Components

SDE - Intern Project42L

June 2020 - August 2020

At Project42L, I primarily worked on launching CMS. I was involved right from designing the models, creating API endpoints, to building a basic panel on the front-end. I was exposed to Wagtail.

Built applications using Wagtail (Django), React and bootstrap

Projects

LiReddit

November 2020 - January 2021

LiReddit is similar to site like Reddit or HackerNews you subscribe to forums you're interested in, post links and discussions, then vote, and comment on them.

Technology Stack

TypeScript,GraphQL,URQL,Node JS, PostgreSQL,TypeORM,Redis,Next JS

https://github.com/kryptocodes/lireddit_frontend

Gate Pass Management System

April 2020 - August 2020

A Complete CMS System, which allows a resident student to apply for his/her Gate Pass Online also generates QR Code when the concerned authority approves the pass. With Four different role dashboard integrated with notification support and offline PWA.

Technology Stack

MongoDB, Mongoose ODM,Express, Node JS, React

https://github.com/kryptocodes/GPMS_backend

https://github.com/kryptocodes/GPMS_frontend

Education

Amrita College of Engineering and Technology - Nagercoil

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

Expected May 2022

Kendriya Vidyalaya - Madurai May 2018